THOMAS DAVID HIBBERS

CURRICULUM VITAE

E-mail	thomas.d.hibbers@gmail.com	WhatsApp	+964 751 179 1493
Website	http://www.thomashibbers.com/	Skype ID	t.hibbers
LinkedIn	linkedin.com/in/thomas-hibbers- 1299802b Skype	Skype No.	+27 127435864



Personal Details:

Born 22 October 1958 in South Africa South African citizen Male Single

A dynamic and experienced teacher, educational leader as well as IB Workshop Leader and School Visiting Team Member with a consistent track record of successfully leading and teaching all aspects of IB PYP, MYP, DP as well as the UK curriculums in multillingual, multicultural community Day Schools and Boarding Schools all over the world.

Areas of Expertise:

 Coordinating IB PYP, MYP and DP 	Bilingual Pedagogy	 Global Citizenship
IB Workshop Leader	 Recruitment and Retention of Staff 	 Curriculum Design
IB School Visiting Team Member	Marketing the school	Financial Management
IB Authorisation	Staff Development	 Online Education

Professional Experience

MAARIF INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL ERBIL • Erbil from 2017 to Present

Previously PYP and MYP Coordinator, Currently Head of International Secondary Schools Coordinating IB MYP and DP: Currently I lead all processes of the International Baccalaureate Diploma and Middle Years Programmes. (Previously my duties included coordinating PYP too, but we had to appoint somebody I trained as PYP coordinator as the school grew bigger). During the time I was coordinating KG and PYP we built a solid foundation of multi-cultural and multilingual language-immersion in Arabic, English, Kurdish and Turkish to prepare our students for a lifetime of global citizenship. Furthermore, we ensured that our students have a strong Mathematics foundation upon which their further studies can be built. As MYP and DP Coordinator I am committed to developing the multi-language ability of our students to the highest international standards. Every member of the team is committed to teaching English in their mainstream classes. The strong Mathematics foundation built in PYP is further developed to prepare our students for the IBDP. To assure top quality teaching, I empower my team with the latest research based cuttingedge teaching research-based teaching strategies with workshops sharing what I learned as IB workshop leader (and continuous IBEN upskill workshops). This is followed up with weekly class visits to monitor, lead and support implementation. After the visit the teacher and I collaboratively review progress and set goals for further improvement at the next visit. My personal leadership style is by example, e.g., teaching PYP PHE, IB MYP Mathematics, etc. These classes are taught using the latest research-based teaching strategies as workshopped to teachers. Student progress is continuously monitored and assessed. The feedback about student progress is shared weekly with students and their parents. I drive the recruitment and onboarding process of staff as a member of the recruitment committee. My duties include collaborating with the Board and Administrators to ensure compliance with IB, CIS and Government standards in our policies, procedures, and teaching schedules. Furthermore, I lead the annual collaborating evaluation, updating and development of policies and procedures. My goal is to establish an organizational culture of positive support and comradery amongst staff taking corporate responsibility for everything at the school. Pastoral care is given by personally following up on the wellbeing of each student and teacher. Staff morale is lifted by nurturing a positive and supportive organization culture and organizing events such as the New Year party for teachers who could not travel home because of the Covid pandemic. Launching the annual orientation of all staff members lays the foundation for the year, training staff in global citizenship, cultural sensitivity, policy review and development, IB teaching methodology, curriculum mapping, benchmarking, and classroom preparation. I am also proud of having a leading part in the marketing drives that raised student enrollment from only two hundred students to more than a thousand students at present.

Key Accomplishments:

- Initiating the vertical alignment of Mathematics and English from KG, PYP, MYP towards IBDP.
- Planning, organizing, leading, and controlling the full language immersion in a multilingual, multicultural Arabic, English, Kurdish, and Turkish community.
- Leading the development of the MYP to full authorization as an IB MYP world school.
- Leading the registration and preparation of the first cohort of IB MYP students for successful eAssessments.
- Improving student behaviour with the implementation of the Positive Behavior Interventions and Supports (PBIS) System.
- Leading the IB Diploma Programme authorization of the school as IBDP Coordinator.
- Improve student grades by introducing SMART targets.
- Spearhead CIS membership to accreditation now.
- Delivered a workshop about financial management of schools to the foundation Heads of Schools in Iraq.

Thomas David Hibbers

MYANMAR INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL from 2015 to 2016 as Business Studies Teacher teaching IGSCE and A/S Level students Business Studies. Developed the new report format while serving as the Leader of the Reporting Committee. Provided emotional support to students on International Week Without Walls trip.

FAIRVIEW INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL from 2014 to 2015 as **School Coordinator**: Serving as the Deputy Principal on one of the school campuses taking pastoral care of students and staff, teaching MYP Individuals and Societies as well as marketing the school.

GUANGZHOU NANHU INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL • Guangzhou, China from 2013 to 2014

Interim Head of Secondary School Leading the Secondary school. Developed strategic plans that aligned with school objectives. Developed staff by giving workshops followed up with class visits. Led by example teaching IBDP Theory of Knowledge and Year 7 History.

Key Accomplishments:

- Finalized the CIS accreditation of the school.
- Led the first inter disciplinary / cross curricular field trip of secondary school to the museum.

INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL AAMBY • Aamby Valley City, India from 2012 to 2013 as **Head of Boarding and School Life**Managed Head of Boarding School duties, which included overseeing boarding of students, developing school activities, and creating budgets. Taught IB Economics and Mathematical studies to ensure school standards were met. Developed strategic plans to highlight priorities, discover resources, and strengthen overall operations for the Boarding School.

Key Accomplishments:

- Promoted to serve as the acting co-principal based on leadership skills and ability to implement programming for student development when the principal left.
- Headed international educational trips to Switzerland and Thailand.

AL-JAZEERA ACADEMY • Doha, Qatar from 2006 to 2012 as Pastoral Coordinator and Teacher

Presided over the Student Representative Council, which included develop plans to guide student behaviour, improve overall school life, and manage school and staff dynamics. Taught CIS Business Studies, IBDP Economics, MYP Mathematics and a PYP Homeroom class.

Key Accomplishments:

- Improved cultural awareness and global citizenship of staff by delivering international mindedness workshops during the orientation of staff.
- Served as a member of the AJA CIS committee to prepare the school for CIS accreditation.

GERT MARITZ SCHOOL • Pietermaritzburg, South Africa • September 1998 - August 2006 as **Whole School Principal/Director**

Headed the management of all school events, duties, and curriculum. Coordinated with Regional Superintendents to coordinate educational standards. Delivered guidance and training on Financial Management and Quality Assurance to Heads of School in the region for the South African government Department of Education.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Boarding School Consultant, GYEONGNAM INTERNATIONAL FOREIGN SCHOOL, Korea Second in Charge, LILYFONTEIN PRIMARY SCHOOL, South Africa
Head of Department, CATHCART HIGH SCHOOL, South Africa
Head of Humanities, ALBERTYN SCHOOL, South Africa
Math/Physical Education Teacher, HANDHAAF SCHOOL, South Africa
Math/Physical Education Teacher, INNES SCHOOL, South Africa

Education, Training and Professional Development

- Master of Business Administration (MBA), University of KwaZulu Natal, South Africa
- Post Graduate Diploma in Management, University of KwaZulu Natal, South Africa
- Bachelor of Commerce, University of Port Elizabeth, South Africa
- Higher Diploma in Education,
 Education, Graaff Reinet Teacher's
 College, South Africa A four-year face to face course equivalent to a B.Ed. degree
- Currently doing my MED Ed. Leadership with The College of New Jersey (TCNJ).

Professional Development Certificates

- IBEN: IB Workshop Leader and School Visiting Team Member.
- PYP: Making the PYP Happen and International Mindedness in the PYP.
- MYP Heads of School/IB Coordinators: Implementing the MYP Curriculum (MYP Coordinator), MYP Mathematics: Delivering the MYP Curriculum Category 1 and 2.
- DP: Leading the learning-DP (DP Coordinator), Teaching Theory of Knowledge (cat 1 and 2), Economics Developments in Teaching, Resourcing and Pedagogy Level 3, Supervising the Extended Essay in Economics, and Internal Assessment Requirements in Economics.
- University of Cambridge: Examinations AS & A-Level Economics.
- **English:** South African Teaching Diploma, Teaching English Second Language Students in Mainstream Classes and TEFL certificate.